{"question":"What is Mrs. Seeber's favorite Disney character?","choice 3":"Sleeping Beauty","choice 4":"Snow White","choice 0":"Mulan","question answer":1,"choice 1":"Elsa","choice 2":"Cinderella"}
{"question":"Which method of waste disposal reduces the volume of waste but could release emissions into the atmosphere?","choice 3":"Chemical treatment","choice 4":"Biological treatment","choice 0":"Sanitary landfill","question answer":1,"choice 1":"Incineration","choice 2":"Discharge to sewers, streams, and rivers"}
{"question":"Which method of waste disposal is used most frequently in the US today?","choice 3":"Discharge to bodies of water","choice 4":"Biological treatment","choice 0":"Incineration","question answer":1,"choice 1":"Sanitary landfill","choice 2":"Chemical treatment"}
{"question":"Which method of waste treatment introduces micro-organisms to break down hazardous organic compounds?","choice 3":"Discharge to bodies of water","choice 4":"Incineration","choice 0":"Biological treatment","question answer":0,"choice 1":"Chemical treatment","choice 2":"Sanitary landfill"}
{"question":"The location where the greatest number of people would be directly affected by a rise in sea level.","choice 3":"The Sahel","choice 4":"Bangladesh","choice 0":"Eastern US","question answer":4,"choice 1":"Northern China","choice 2":"The Amazon Rainforest"}
{"question":"The location with the greatest remaining biodiversity is:","choice 3":"The Amazon Rainforest","choice 4":"The Sahel","choice 0":"Western US","question answer":3,"choice 1":"Eastern Australia","choice 2":"Northwestern India"}
{"question":"The location where desertification is occurring most rapidly:","choice 3":"Siberia","choice 4":"The Atacama Desert","choice 0":"Central Mexico","question answer":1,"choice 1":"The Sahel","choice 2":"Northeastern India"}
{"question":"Exemplified by ticks feeding on a deer:","choice 3":"Predation","choice 4":"Competition","choice 0":"Commensalism","question answer":1,"choice 1":"Parasitism","choice 2":"Mutualism"}
{"question":"Exemplified by starlings displacing bluebirds from nesting sites:","choice 3":"Competition","choice 4":"Predation","choice 0":"Parasitism","question answer":3,"choice 1":"Commensalism","choice 2":"Mutualism"}
{"question":"\"Matter in motion has energy\" is represented by:","choice 3":"Zeroth Law of Thermodynamics","choice 4":"Kinetic Energy","choice 0":"Heat Flow","question answer":4,"choice 1":"Potential Energy","choice 2":"Magnetic Energy"}
{"question":"\"Energy is transferred from one object to another as the result of a temperature difference\" is represented by:","choice 3":"Zeroth Law of Thermodynamics","choice 4":"Electricity","choice 0":"Third Law of Thermodynamics","question answer":2,"choice 1":"Kinetic Energy","choice 2":"Heat Flow"}
{"question":"This source of energy is commonly used in Iceland:","choice 3":"Tidal Energy","choice 4":"Sunlight","choice 0":"Wind","question answer":1,"choice 1":"Geothermal","choice 2":"Nuclear Fission"}
{"question":"This source of energy creates long-lived hazardous wastes:","choice 3":"Sunlight","choice 4":"Wind","choice 0":"Geothermal","question answer":2,"choice 1":"Nuclear Fusion","choice 2":"Nuclear Fission"}
{"question":"This source of energy is not renewable:","choice 3":"Wind","choice 4":"Tidal Energy","choice 0":"Biomass","question answer":1,"choice 1":"Nuclear Fission","choice 2":"Geothermal"}
{"question":"This is an important precursor to acid rain","choice 3":"Sulfur dioxide","choice 4":"Carbon dioxide","choice 0":"Carbon monoxide","question answer":3,"choice 1":"Methane","choice 2":"Radon"}
{"question":"This gas has a stronger affinity for hemoglobin than oxygen:","choice 3":"Sarin gas","choice 4":"Ammonia","choice 0":"Carbon dioxide","question answer":1,"choice 1":"Carbon monoxide","choice 2":"Nitrogen"}
{"question":"The following is caused by suspended particulates:","choice 3":"Salinity","choice 4":"Dissolved Oxygen","choice 0":"Acidity","question answer":1,"choice 1":"Turbidity","choice 2":"Hardness"}
{"question":"The following is measured by the amount of calcium and magnesium ions:","choice 3":"Dissolved Oxygen","choice 4":"Hardness","choice 0":"Turbidity","question answer":4,"choice 1":"Salinity","choice 2":"Acidity"}
{"question":"Ozone in the stratosphere is important to organisms at Earth's surface because ozone molecules absorb:","choice 3":"infrared rays","choice 4":"gamma rays","choice 0":"x-rays","question answer":2,"choice 1":"visible light rays","choice 2":"ultraviolet rays"}
{"question":"The National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 required all agencies responsible for a major federal project with environmental consequences to file:","choice 3":"A geographic information systems report","choice 4":"An environmental impact statement","choice 0":"A cost-benefit analysis","question answer":4,"choice 1":"An agency review","choice 2":"A migitated negative declaration"}
{"question":"All of the following are considered toxic metal pollutants except:","choice 3":"Potassium","choice 4":"Cadmium","choice 0":"Chromium","question answer":3,"choice 1":"Lead","choice 2":"Mercury"}
{"question":"Which of the following actions would be the most effective in decreasing acid rain problems?","choice 3":"Adding lime to acidified lakes","choice 4":"Relocating power plants to low-density areas","choice 0":"Reducing fossil fuel use","question answer":0,"choice 1":"Using higher somkestacks","choice 2":"Developing acid-resistant crops"}
{"question":"In general, which solution is the best long-term method of preventing extinctions?","choice 3":"Removing predators from areas that contain endangered species","choice 4":"Protecting the habitats of endangered species","choice 0":"Providing food to endangered species in the wild","question answer":4,"choice 1":"Breeding endangered species in captivity","choice 2":"Paying people not to kill endangered species"}
{"question":"What would most likely occur in a forested region that has been recently clear-cut?","choice 3":"The water temperature in streams running through the region will decrease","choice 4":"The concentration of nitrates in streams in the region will decrease","choice 0":"The volume of runoff after rains will increase","question answer":0,"choice 1":"The frequency of landslides will decrease","choice 2":"The average depth of topsoil will increase"}
{"question":"Zero population growth is associated with what phase of the demographic transition?","choice 3":"Phase IV only","choice 4":"Phases I and IV","choice 0":"Phase I only","question answer":4,"choice 1":"Phase II only","choice 2":"Phase III only"}
{"question":"The rate of population growth starts to slow at what point in the demographic transition?","choice 3":"The end of Phase III","choice 4":"The middle of Phase IV","choice 0":"The end of Phase I","question answer":2,"choice 1":"The middle of Phase II","choice 2":"The beginning of Phase III"}
{"question":"What is most likely the primary cause of high deaths rates in Phase I of the demographic transition?","choice 3":"General starvation due to famine","choice 4":"Infant and childhood mortality","choice 0":"Loss of breeding-age females due to disease","question answer":4,"choice 1":"Loss of breeding-age males due to warfare","choice 2":"Large percentage of elderly individuals in the population"}
{"question":"Which of the following best shows the process of evolution?","choice 3":"A giraffe's neck becomes longer as it stretches for food","choice 4":"A plant loses leaves in a drought","choice 0":"Humans genetically modify farm crops","question answer":1,"choice 1":"A population of weeds develop resistance to a herbicide","choice 2":"A lizard's color becomes brown as it sits on a log"}
{"question":"Most data indicate that, during the 20th century, mean global annual temperature has: ","choice 3":"Increased by 0.5 degrees Celsius","choice 4":"Increased by 5 degrees Celsius","choice 0":"Decreased by 5 degrees Celsius","question answer":3,"choice 1":"Decreased by 0.5 degrees Celsius","choice 2":"Stayed the same"}
{"question":"Environmentalists oppose the mining of the Antarctic because: ","choice 3":"Current known world reserves of important metals and oils are considered inexhaustible","choice 4":"The demand for minerals is expected to decline as nations industrialize","choice 0":"Territorial claims to Antarctica are unresolved","question answer":2,"choice 1":"The existence of economically viable mineral deposits is unlikely","choice 2":"The polar environment is fragile and extremely vulnerable to the disturbance that would accompany development"}
{"question":"Fragmenting one large nature preserve into many small parks with human habitation in between them is most likely to lead to: ","choice 3":"Increase in gene flow within species","choice 4":"Increase in population size of top carnivores","choice 0":"Stabilization of microclimates","question answer":1,"choice 1":"Reduction in species diversity","choice 2":"Decrease in the proportion in edge habitat"}
{"question":"Which of the following metals is considered to be a potential energy resource?","choice 3":"Copper","choice 4":"Manganese","choice 0":"Cobalt","question answer":2,"choice 1":"Iron","choice 2":"Thorium"}
{"question":"Of the following, which constitutes the greatest percent of domestic water use in the US?","choice 3":"Washing clothes","choice 4":"Washing dishes","choice 0":"Drinking","question answer":1,"choice 1":"Flushing toilets","choice 2":"Cooking"}
{"question":"Which of the following best describes soils in many tropical rain forests?","choice 3":"They are well suited to growing a wide variety of crops","choice 4":"They are deep and well drained","choice 0":"They lack soil horizons","question answer":1,"choice 1":"They are quickly depleted of nutrients when the forest is removed","choice 2":"They are similar to soils in coniferous forests"}
{"question":"Which of the following elements constitutes the highest percentage of mass in Earth's crust?","choice 3":"Iron","choice 4":"Silicon","choice 0":"Carbon","question answer":2,"choice 1":"Aluminium","choice 2":"Oxygen"}
{"question":"If an incandescent lightbulb is used for lighting has an efficiency rating of 10%, then for every joule of electrical energy consumed, which of the following is produced?","choice 3":"0.10 joules of heat energy","choice 4":"1.10 joules of light energy","choice 0":"1.05 joules of heat energy","question answer":1,"choice 1":"0.90 joules of heat energy","choice 2":"0.90 joules of light energy"}
{"question":"Sunlight is the ultimate source of energy for the following communities except for: ","choice 3":"The open ocean","choice 4":"The profundal zone","choice 0":"Tropical rain forests","question answer":2,"choice 1":"Polar ice caps","choice 2":"Hydrothermal vents"}
{"question":"The majority of a terrestrial plant's mass comes from: ","choice 3":"Water","choice 4":"Fertilizer","choice 0":"Nutrients in the soil","question answer":1,"choice 1":"Carbon in the air","choice 2":"Sunlight"}
{"question":"All of the following gases are GHGs except for: ","choice 3":"diatomic oxygen","choice 4":"water vapor","choice 0":"methane","question answer":3,"choice 1":"carbon dioxide","choice 2":"nitrous oxide"}
{"question":"A country undergoing extremely rapid population growth is: ","choice 3":"Bangladesh","choice 4":"France","choice 0":"Niger","question answer":0,"choice 1":"Hungary","choice 2":"Kazakhstan"}
{"question":"A country undergoing rapid economic growth (as of 2016) is: ","choice 3":"India","choice 4":"The United States","choice 0":"Argentina","question answer":3,"choice 1":"Brazil","choice 2":"Germany"}
{"question":"A country that is past Stage III of the demographic transition is: ","choice 3":"Afghanistan","choice 4":"Poland","choice 0":"Madagascar","question answer":4,"choice 1":"Sierra Leone","choice 2":"Pakistan"}
{"question":"The major reservoirs of nitrogen and sulfur in the biosphere are, respectively: ","choice 3":"Atmosphere, Rocks","choice 4":"Vegetation, Rocks","choice 0":"Rocks, Atmosphere","question answer":3,"choice 1":"Rocks, Vegetation","choice 2":"Vegetation, Atmosphere"}
{"question":"a sample of radioactive waste has a half-life of 10 years and an activity level of 4 curies. After how many years will the activity level of this sample be 0.25 curie?","choice 3":"40 years","choice 4":"80 years","choice 0":"10 years","question answer":3,"choice 1":"20 years","choice 2":"30 years"}
{"question":"The third-most abundant gas in Earth's atmosphere is: ","choice 3":"Carbon Dioxide","choice 4":"Argon","choice 0":"Nitrogen","question answer":4,"choice 1":"Oxygen","choice 2":"Water Vapor"}
{"question":"Which of the following would most likely have the greatest positive impact on the quality of the natural environment worldwide?","choice 3":"Increased reliance on ocean ecosystems for protein","choice 4":"Stabilization or reduction of the size of the human population","choice 0":"Discovery of new reserves of fossil fuels in Saudi Arabia","question answer":4,"choice 1":"Increaed agricultural production on marginal desert lands","choice 2":"Increased life expectancy in developed nations"}
{"question":"All of the following are derived from petroleum except: ","choice 3":"nylon","choice 4":"rayon","choice 0":"Polystyrene","question answer":4,"choice 1":"DDT","choice 2":"asphalt"}
{"question":"Most volcanism in the world is associated with: ","choice 3":"Climate change","choice 4":"faulting","choice 0":"Plate boundaries","question answer":0,"choice 1":"Faulting","choice 2":"Desertification"}
{"question":"Compared with people in developing countries, people in industrialized countries are more likely to eat","choice 3":"Wheat","choice 4":"Beans","choice 0":"Pork","question answer":0,"choice 1":"Corn","choice 2":"Rice"}
{"question":"The current world population is closest to which of the following: ","choice 3":"15 billion","choice 4":"100 billion","choice 0":"100 million","question answer":2,"choice 1":"1 billion","choice 2":"10 billion"}
{"question":"Which of the following is most likely to result from the destruction of wetlands surrounding a river?","choice 3":"Increases in dissolved oxygen (DO) levels in the river","choice 4":"An increased diversity of river aquatic species","choice 0":"A decreased sediment load in the river","question answer":2,"choice 1":"Decreases in nitrate levels in the river","choice 2":"An increased risk of flooding of the river valley"}
{"question":"The presence of low levels of dissolved oxygen (DO) can indicate that the water: ","choice 3":"Has been contaminated by untreated human or animal waste","choice 4":"Is likely to cause cancer","choice 0":"Is safe to drink","question answer":3,"choice 1":"Is safe to swim in","choice 2":"Has been recently treated at a sewage treatment plant"}
{"question":"Of the following, what is the biggest immediate problem with sanitary landfills?","choice 3":"Incomplete degredation of wastes","choice 4":"Release of disease organisms","choice 0":"Generation of carbon dioxide gas","question answer":1,"choice 1":"Leachate contamination of groundwater","choice 2":"Contamination of the surrounding ground with dioxin"}
{"question":"Of the following organisms, which occupies the lowest tropic level?","choice 3":"Frog","choice 4":"Snake","choice 0":"Spider","question answer":1,"choice 1":"Deer","choice 2":"Lion"}
{"question":"Which of the following has been connected with the Keeling Curve, which shows atmospheric CO2 concentration versus time?","choice 3":"The number of plants on the Earth has been decreasing","choice 4":"The extent of the polar ice caps has been increasing","choice 0":"Energy output from the Sun has increased","question answer":1,"choice 1":"Humans have emmitted large quantities of CO2, largely from combustion of fossil fuels","choice 2":"Volcanos are releasing large quantities of sulfur compounds into the atmosphere"}
{"question":"Which of the following is most likely to be the direct result of lack of genetic diversity in a food crop like corn?","choice 3":"Increased susceptibility to plant disease","choice 4":"Increased resistance to pests","choice 0":"Decreased kernel size","question answer":3,"choice 1":"Decreased potential yield","choice 2":"Decreased dependence on chemical fertilizers"}
{"question":"Which of the following gases is released by CFCs and catalyses reactions that break down ozone in the stratosphere?","choice 3":"Chlorine","choice 4":"Mustard gas","choice 0":"Carbon monoxide","question answer":3,"choice 1":"Ammonia","choice 2":"Sulfur dioxide"}
{"question":"The major biological source of dissolved oxygen in the oceans comes from: ","choice 3":"Photosynthesis by phytoplankton","choice 4":"Photosynthesis by terrestrial plants","choice 0":"Decomposition of sediment on the ocean floor","question answer":3,"choice 1":"Oxidation of sulfur by bacterial in hydrothermal vent communities","choice 2":"Metabolic processes of coral in reefs"}
{"question":"Overfishing of the high seas is an example of the: ","choice 3":"Principle of manifest destiny","choice 4":"Effects of the fall of the British Empire","choice 0":"Swapping of debt for nature","question answer":2,"choice 1":"Ideology of communism","choice 2":"Tragedy of the commons"}
{"question":"In contrast to low-level radioactive waste, most high-level waste is currently","choice 3":"Incinerated","choice 4":"Put into steel drums and disposed of in sanitary landiflls","choice 0":"Stored at the Yucca Mountain facility in Arizona","question answer":1,"choice 1":"Kept at reactor sites","choice 2":"Launched into outer space"}
{"question":"The main environmental effects of ozone depletion could include all of the following except: ","choice 3":"Reduction of primary productivity in the oceans","choice 4":"Increased incidence of skin cancer","choice 0":"Disruption of marine food chains","question answer":2,"choice 1":"Lower food-crop production","choice 2":"Decreased concentration of CO2 in the atmosphere"}
{"question":"A nuclear war can cause all of the following except:  ","choice 3":"Increase global primary productivity","choice 4":"Political instability and unrest","choice 0":"Depletion of the ozone layer","question answer":3,"choice 1":"Lower food-crop production","choice 2":"Decreased global temperatures"}
{"question":"The primary cause of the Earth's seasons is: ","choice 3":"Changing distance of Earth from the Sun at different times of the year","choice 4":"Constant tilt of Earth's axis with respect to the plane of its orbit around the Sun","choice 0":"Changing relative positions of the Earth, Sun, and Moon","question answer":4,"choice 1":"Periodic changes in solar energy output","choice 2":"Periodic wobbling of the Earth's axis of rotation"}
{"question":"The various stages in the formation of coal, in order, are: ","choice 3":"Peat, bituminous, lignite, anthracite","choice 4":"Lignite, bituminous, anthracite, peat","choice 0":"Bituminous, peat, lignite, anthracite","question answer":1,"choice 1":"Peat, lignite, bituminous, anthracite","choice 2":"Anthracite, bituminous, lignite, peat"}
{"question":"Order the methods of solid-waste management from least energy to most energy required","choice 3":"Recycle, reuse, reduce","choice 4":"Reduce, recycle, reuse","choice 0":"Reduce, reuse, recycle","question answer":0,"choice 1":"Reuse, reduce, recycle","choice 2":"Recycle, reuse, reduce"}
{"question":"While stratospheric ozone is desirable, tropospheric ozone is bad because it ","choice 3":"Has a different chemical structure from stratospheric ozone","choice 4":"Increases atmospheric CO2 concentrations","choice 0":"Absorbs UV light","question answer":1,"choice 1":"is a strong oxidant and a respiratory irritant","choice 2":"Reacts with hydrocarbons to form CFCs"}
{"question":"In models of global warming, the most important factor contributing to sea level rise is ","choice 3":"Decreased evaporation","choice 4":"Growth of heat islands","choice 0":"Thermal expansion of the oceans","question answer":0,"choice 1":"Increased precipitation","choice 2":"Subsurface ocean cooling"}
{"question":"Which of the following best explains why toxins are highly concentrated in the breast milk of the Inuit peoples?","choice 3":"Increased population growth has led to the depletion of fish stocks that formed the traditional diet of the Inuit","choice 4":"Chemicals like DDT and dioxin are volatile and eventually make their way to the mesosphere","choice 0":"Chemicals produced in one region of the world can circulate in the biosphere and affect organisms in distant regions","question answer":0,"choice 1":"DDT and other toxins were applied against native peoples during Canada's territorial expansion","choice 2":"Although dioxin is toxic to babies, it has no effect on adult humans"}
{"question":"What is the best example of a point source of water pollution?","choice 3":"Agricultural runoff","choice 4":"Litter","choice 0":"Factory effluent","question answer":0,"choice 1":"Storm water","choice 2":"Acid deposition"}
{"question":"Road construction, logging, and mining are banned in which of the following federal lands?","choice 3":"National resource lands","choice 4":"National forests","choice 0":"National parks","question answer":2,"choice 1":"National wildlife refuges","choice 2":"National wilderness preservation areas"}
{"question":"Which of the following best describes the mechanism of the greenhouse effect in the Earth's atmosphere?","choice 3":"Cosmic radiation from deep space is absorbed by industrial pollutants in the atmosphere","choice 4":"Visible light from the sun is absorbed directly by the atmosphere","choice 0":"UV radiation from the sun is absorbed by ozone gas in the stratosphere","question answer":2,"choice 1":"Gamma radiation from the Sun is absorbed at ground level by dust particles in the atmosphere","choice 2":"Infrared radiation from Earth's surface is absorbed by gases in the atmosphere"}
{"question":"In a human population undergoing the demographic transition, which of the following generally decreases first?","choice 3":"Average family size","choice 4":"Gross domestic product","choice 0":"Birth rate","question answer":1,"choice 1":"Death rate","choice 2":"Population growth rate"}
{"question":"Which of the following is generally considered an organic compound?","choice 3":"Cyanide","choice 4":"Water","choice 0":"Table salt","question answer":2,"choice 1":"Carbon dioxide","choice 2":"Ethane"}
{"question":"High rates of species extinction caused by human activities have taken place at what of the following times in Earth's history?","choice 3":"The Cretaceous-Tertiary Extnction","choice 4":"Recent times","choice 0":"Snowball Earth","question answer":4,"choice 1":"The Oxygen Catastrophe","choice 2":"The Permian-Triassic Extinction"}
{"question":"In the US, the largest single component of municipal solid waste (MSW) is: ","choice 3":"Paper","choice 4":"Food scraps","choice 0":"Glass","question answer":3,"choice 1":"Scrap metal","choice 2":"Plastic"}
{"question":"Which country has the largest coal reserves? ","choice 3":"The United States","choice 4":"Iran","choice 0":"Saudi Arabia","question answer":3,"choice 1":"Russia","choice 2":"India"}
{"question":"Which of the following will result in cultural eutrophication when introduced into streams, lakes, and bays?","choice 3":"Phosphate fertilizer","choice 4":"Herbicides","choice 0":"Biological agents","question answer":3,"choice 1":"Pesticides","choice 2":"Fly ash"}
{"question":"The two major processes involved in the carbon cycle are: ","choice 3":"Photosynthesis and respiration","choice 4":"Fixation and denitrification","choice 0":"Weathering and erosion","question answer":3,"choice 1":"Erosion and deposition","choice 2":"Evaporation and transpiration"}
{"question":"Two major processes involved in the nitrogen cycle are: ","choice 3":"Photosynthesis and respiration","choice 4":"Fixation and denitrification","choice 0":"Weathering and erosion","question answer":4,"choice 1":"Erosion and deposition","choice 2":"Evaporation and transpiration"}
{"question":"Besides global climate change, what is another damaging effect of increasing atmospheric CO2 concentrations?","choice 3":"Increased rates of fossil fuel formation","choice 4":"Increased abundance of oceanic plankton","choice 0":"Acidification of the oceans","question answer":0,"choice 1":"Increased net primary productivity","choice 2":"Decreased levels of trophospheric ozone"}
{"question":"Which of the following would be best for remediating the effects of soil salinization?","choice 3":"Application of broad-spectrum biocides to kill pathogenic organisms","choice 4":"Application of lime to raise soil pH","choice 0":"Application of superphosphate to increase soil fertility","question answer":1,"choice 1":"Addition of large amounts of water to leach out salts","choice 2":"Addition of clay to increase soil water-holding capacity"}
{"question":"What is an example of a uniform species distribution?","choice 3":"Humans migrating to rapidly expanding urban areas","choice 4":"Crabs occupying hydrothermal vents","choice 0":"Bison travelling in herds","question answer":1,"choice 1":"Wheat planted in straight rows","choice 2":"Dandelions clumped into small groups"}
{"question":"All of the following are characteristic of the euphotic zone except: ","choice 3":"It extends to around 200 meters below the surface in the open ocean","choice 4":"Species include bluefin tuna and flying fish","choice 0":"It has access to sunlight","question answer":2,"choice 1":"It has the highest primary productivity","choice 2":"Fish that live there tend not to have eyes"}
{"question":"A fish that's tolerant of cold water and has a flattened body to live under stone would most likely be found in which zone of a stream?","choice 3":"Delta zone","choice 4":"Littoral zone","choice 0":"Source zone","question answer":0,"choice 1":"Transition zone","choice 2":"Floodplain zone"}
{"question":"Which of the following is one of the primary threats to mangrove forests?","choice 3":"Mining","choice 4":"Agriculture","choice 0":"Shrimp farming","question answer":0,"choice 1":"Oil and gas exploration","choice 2":"Mosquito eradication"}
{"question":"Why are oxygen levels lower in the profundal zone of a freshwater lake?","choice 3":"It is the area first affected by agricultural runoff","choice 4":"Low numbers of fish use up oxygen","choice 0":"High numbers of fish use up oxygen","question answer":1,"choice 1":"Low light levels decrease photosynthesis","choice 2":"High levels of algae use up the oxygen"}
{"question":"Fires that burn away flammable ground material and help prevent more destructive fires are called: ","choice 3":"High intensity fires","choice 4":"Low intensity fires","choice 0":"Crown fires","question answer":2,"choice 1":"Ground fires","choice 2":"Surface fires"}
{"question":"All of the following can potentially prevent the Tragedy of the Commons except: ","choice 3":"A tradable permit system","choice 4":"Imposing a tax on equipment used to extract the resource","choice 0":"Assigning property rights","question answer":2,"choice 1":"Imposing extraction quotas","choice 2":"Subsidies for using the resource"}
{"question":"Integrated Pest Management (IPM) utilizes which of the following? ","choice 3":"Mechanical controls, e.g. traps and physical destruction of pest breeding grounds","choice 4":"All of the above","choice 0":"Biological pest control, e.g. ladybugs that eat pest insects like aphids","question answer":4,"choice 1":"Chemical pesticides (up to a certain extent)","choice 2":"Planting crops that are resistant to pests"}
{"question":"All of the following are true of the El Nino-Southern Oscillation (ENSO) except:  ","choice 3":"The typical monsoon season in the Western Pacific is disrputed, and sometimes there are droughts","choice 4":"It changes the distribution patterns of pelagic marine species","choice 0":"It occurs regularly, every five years, in the Pacific","question answer":0,"choice 1":"The prevailing winds in the tropical Pacific weaken and change directions","choice 2":"The warming of the Eastern Pacific causes a reduction in upwelling nutrients and an increase in rainfall"}
